A Guide to the Foundation for Child Development records FA019
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grant Programs, 1911, 1946-1996, bulk 1960-1996; bulk; 4
  - Young Scholars Program, 1982-1991; 6
    - Research Projects, 1982-1991; 2
      - Ann Crouter, 1985-1987 (Reel 105, Frame 1127)
      - Richard J. Davidson, 1982-1984 (Reel 106, Frame 1)
      - Theodore Dix, 1990-1991 (Reel 106, Frame 172)
      - Kenneth A. Dodge, 1984-1986 (Reel 106, Frame 196)
      - Nancy Eisenberg, 1983-1984 (Reel 106, Frame 313)
      - Wendy A. Goldberg, 1987 (Reel 106, Frame 403)
      - H. Hill Goldsmith, 1982 (Reel 106, Frame 584)
      - Karen Gouze, 1983 (Reel 106, Frame 598)
      - William G. Graziano, 1983 (Reel 106, Frame 611)
      - Megan R. Gunnar, 1984 (Reel 106, Frame 655)
      - Dale F. Hay, 1984 (Reel 106, Frame 686)
      - Bruce B. Henderson, 1985 (Reel 106, Frame 740)
      - Patrick A. Holleran, 1983 (Reel 106, Frame 802)
      - Anne P. Humphreys, 1983, 1987 (Reel 106, Frame 854)
      - Marion C. Hyson, 1984 (Reel 106, Frame 964)
      - Sandra W. Jacobson, 1984, 1991 (Reel 106, Frame 1047)
      - Lyle S. Joffe, 1984 (Reel 107, Frame 1)
      - Diane Carlson Jones, 1985 (Reel 107, Frame 29)
      - Paul A. Jose, 1986 (Reel 107, Frame 37)
      - Saul M. Kassin, 1986 (Reel 107, Frame 43)
      - Gary W. Ladd, 1985, 1988 (Reel 107, Frame 89)
      - Carol Z. Malatesta, 1986 (Reel 107, Frame 147)
      - Sharon Nelson-Le Gall, 1983 (Reel 107, Frame 163)
      - Andrew F. Newcomb, 1984 (Reel 107, Frame 205)
      - Deborah Phillips, 1984, 1986 (Reel 107, Frame 236)
      - Sandra L. Pipp, 1984 (Reel 107, Frame 436)
      - Thomas G. Power, 1984 (Reel 107, Frame 467)
      - Nancy Rader, 1983 (Reel 107, Frame 478)
      - Lela Sarnat, 1984 (Reel 107, Frame 482)
      - Judith G. Smetana, 1985 (Reel 107, Frame 521)
      - Janet Strayer, 1983 (Reel 107, Frame 548)
      - Ross A. Thompson, 1986 (Reel 107, Frame 592)
      - Judy A. Ungerer, 1984 (Reel 107, Frame 635)
      - Jaan Valsinger, 1983 (Reel 107, Frame 661)
      - Deborah Lowe Vandell, 1988 (Reel 107, Frame 720)
      - Brian E. Vaughn, 1985, 1987 (Reel 107, Frame 738)
      - Everett Waters, 1984 (Reel 107, Frame 807)
- Audio-Visual Materials, 6
  The photographs have also been microfilmed in their original location in the files.
  Photographs accompanying collection material and audio cassette tapes representing certain oral history interviews comprise this series.
  Interviews were conducted with eleven members of the council, who served terms between 1951 and 1955. These interviews provide a perspective of the post-WWII Foundation and the development of the organization after the acceptance of the Belding funds. This historical information was intended to supplement the Foundation's narrative history written by Alice FitzGerald. The taped interviews are with Emily McFarland, April 26-27, 1994 (2 cassette tapes); Kathleen Mortimer, April 14, 1994 (1 cassette tape); and George Wheatley, April 14, 1994 (1 cassette tape). There are also two reels of magnetic tape concerning the Foundation's Seventy-Fifth Anniversary, February 4, 1975, and its Annual Meeting, September 28, 1979.
  Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference. The oral history interviews on four audio cassettes are fragile and are not available for playback.
  Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (audio) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.